Do you ever wonder why your revenue is
absolutely brilliant one month and then
it's dead the next even when you're
working hard from month to month? Well,
you've probably got deliverables nailed.
But the sales side of things is a
completely different story. Most
business owners are winning deals on
talent and hustle and hoping that the
referrals keep coming in and that's
what's driving this feast and famine
revenue cycle that you're probably
experiencing. So, in this video, I'm
going to show you the six components of
the sales system that's going to make
your revenue predictable so you can go
out there, make way more money, and have
importantly a much more stable business
as well. Now, most service business
owners have built something genuinely
impressive. A delivery process that runs
the same way every time, gets results,
and keeps clients coming back for more.
And then you look at how you win those
clients in the first place, and it's
referrals. It's hoping that the phone
rings, it's a whole bunch of nothing,
basically. And and that should make you
feel a little bit uncomfortable because
if you think about the two halves of
your business and how systematized they
are well on the delivery side, you've
probably got a process in place and it
works. You know what happens on day one.
You know what happens on week two with
the client. A new team member could join
the team and they could run it and they
could have success. A client could
probably describe what they're getting
and when they're going to get it. And
that's why your clients stay and that's
why you get referrals in the first place
because the deliverables and the
experience that your clients receiving
is so consistent. But from the sales
side of things, well, it's whoever
happens to stumble into your inbox or
drop you a line. It's the referral that
came in because a current client
randomly mentioned you in a conversation
with one of their friends. You perhaps
follow up with prospects, but only when
you remember to do so. and you're
probably checking your CRM on a Monday
morning, realizing they haven't spoke to
a new prospect in 3 weeks, panicking and
putting together some prospecting
activity. So whilst your deliverables
run on a documented repeated process,
your sales runs on a bit of luck and
then random spurts of sales activity
when you start to panic about the
revenue that is or probably isn't coming
in next quarter. And that gap is exactly
what causes this boom and bust cycle
that most service business owners are
stuck in. revenue dips. So, you go into
panic mode. You start hustling for new
clients. You get busy again. And the
moment that you're busy, you take your
foot off the gas. You have a a bit of a
chill, and then you stop selling
because, well, you don't got time
because you do all this client work
instead. And these frantic months, and
then the quiet months, well, they're not
random. And I've seen this from working
with over 1,100 business owners at this
point. They are the predictable result
of a sales process that only runs when
you're desperate enough to get your bum
in the chair and start doing your
prospecting activities. And the craziest
thing about all this from my perspective
is that most business owners tell
themselves that this is due to a lack of
time. They just don't have the time to
get these sales activities done each
week. And if they just had a little bit
more room to breathe, they'd sort the
sales side of things out. However, in my
experience, again, dealing with over a
thousand business owners at this point
who have generated over $1.4 billion
using my sales systems. Well, the reason
you don't have time is because you've
not got the sales system in place in the
first place. And that's exactly what I'm
going to help you with with this video.
But before you can build any sales
system, you need to understand one key
question. And that key question is
answered once when a business owner like
yourself first start up their business.
They file it away and then that's the
last time they think about it. And that
is a problem because the answer to this
question is what the entirety the whole
sales system rests on top of. And so
we've got to make sure that we've got it
right. Now, the instinct for most
business owners is to say that, well, we
will work with anyone who needs what we
do. And that feels like the right thing
to say because it keeps your options
open. But your messaging then at that
point from the very top of your sales
process has to speak to everyone and so
ends up speaking to absolutely no one.
The prospect reads your cold outreach or
your ads and they think, "Yeah, this
might be for me, but it might not be for
me." They're unsure and so they don't
book a call. they don't progress through
the sales process because if they can't
answer the question at a glance in less
than a second of is this offer very
specifically for me and my problem,
they're just going to move on. And from
your perspective, this can be super
frustrating knowing that you can really
help someone solve a painful business
problem, but they're just not giving you
the time for you to really help them
understand the depth of this problem and
how you can help them on a quick call.
And this is what your ICP fixes. So this
is your ideal customer profile and the
whole point of it is to get specific
enough about the people that you deliver
the most value to so that when they see
the messaging that you've built around
your ICP they go hey that that is
literally me. I have that exact problem
and that exact solution is what I've
been looking hoping to find and so they
book a call on your calendar and they
want to learn more. Perfect. Right now
to give you a bit of contrast here to to
make this real for you here are two
emails. So the first email goes hi the
person's name I help business owners
increase their revenue. makes sense to
jump a quick call and I'll explain how.
Then you got the second email of I help
business owners of service-based
businesses doing between $20,000 and
$200,000 a month find and close more
deals in the next 30 days or your money
back. We do this by implementing a
simple selling system that eliminates
the up and down roller coaster of sales
that you're probably on right now. Make
sense? Jump on a quick call and I'll
explain how. So, two emails, just a few
more words from one to the other and
hopefully you can see the difference
there. If you are a business owner, if
you receive this email and you're a
business owner who sells a service, who
is on the roller coaster of sales and
you're within that revenue range, i.e.
you are within a very specific ICP, then
you're way more likely to think, hm,
this looks perfectly suited to me, and
you're going to reply way more often to
the second email over the more general
and broad first one. So, that's the
power of narrowing down your ICP. And
what you're thinking right now is, well,
why why do I want to go after a thousand
people rather than 50,000 people? Well,
the answer is you're going to close a
much higher percentage of those 1,000
people with a very specific ICP than the
much lower percentage that you're going
to close of that much broader, more
generic audience that you're probably
trying to go after right now. So, how do
you narrow down the ideal person in the
first place? Well, you want to start
with the clients that you've already got
great results from working with already.
You don't want to reinvent the wheel
with any of this if you don't have to.
What you should do is just ask yourself,
what did they have in common? And don't
stop at the obvious stuff either. So
things like industry or company size,
they're a good starting point, but
they're not enough to really narrow down
your ICP on their own. What we're really
looking for is the specific pain they
were battling when they came to you and
what made them ready to act now rather
than at some random point in the future.
And that very specific combination of
the problem plus the trigger is going to
tell you exactly who's going to book a
call and buy right now rather than
someone who might book a call maybe and
might theoretically be interested at
some point in the future. And it's much
more profitable to spend time with
people who want to buy right now rather
than trying to convince someone who
isn't yet sold on changing their ways
that they should work with you at some
point in the future. And every part of
the sales system that you're about to
build, how you find prospects, what you
say to them, how you run discovery
calls, all of this only works if it's
aimed at that right person from the
start. This is why it's so important to
build out your ICP. So now you know
exactly who you're targeting. The next
question is how you find those people in
the marketplace and then jump on a quick
call with them. Because without a
repeatable process to book meetings,
lead generation is going to remain
something that you you only do when
you're in a panic and when you check
your bank account and it's looking a
little bit empty. Now, having worked
with a bunch of businesses over at
salesman.com over the past 10 years,
what does the service business lead
generation process typically look like?
Well, it typically looks like a complete
mess of just ad hoc bits and pieces here
and there. The business owners are
waiting for referrals. They're DMing
random people on LinkedIn when they
realize that they've got no meetings
booked in for that next week. They're
hoping that someone reaches out based on
the Google ads that they've hired some
random young inexperienced person to run
because they just can't be asked to
learn the paid ads themselves. And the
reason that this keeps you stuck in this
boom and bust loop is that it's almost
all reactive. You're not running a
system that generates leads. Instead,
you're hoping that they just magically
appear and fall into your lap. And a
repeatable process looks completely
different to this. It means following
the same steps in the same order every
single time, regardless of regardless of
how boring the process is, and also
regarding of how busy you are. If you
want to make a bunch of money running a
business that sells a service, there are
going to be some boring parts to the
sales process. The good news is is that
once we systematize them all, you can
hand them off to someone else to run.
So, they're not going to be boring
forever. And the starting point to
building this prospecting part of the
overall sales system is figuring out
where your ICP lives. So, what platforms
are they on? What communities are they
spending time in? What events do they
physically show up to in, you know,
heaven forbid you go somewhere in the
real world to do some prospecting? What
are some of the signals that tell you
that someone is ready to have a
conversation with you right now? Because
once you know where your ICP is, you can
then build a process to reach them at
the right moment and book meetings again
super reliably. In fact, all you need to
do to fill your calendar every single
month is just focus on three simple
things. finding the right person at the
right time and then putting the right
message in front of them. That is
literally it. I've worked with business
owners at this point who've been trying
to crack this cold outreach puzzle for
for years if not decades with very
little luck and very little success who
start consistently booking meetings when
they narrow down the focus to just
getting those three things sorted. And
then there's the outreach itself. Right?
So, for most business owners who are
selling a service that costs more than
$5 to $10,000, you want to do the
opposite of what everyone here on
YouTube is telling you to do right now.
You don't want to do mass AI slop emails
over 50 different random domains. It's
just not going to work for you. Instead,
where we're seeing a lot of success of
our clients right now is targeted
messages going to the right people at
exactly the right moments. And of
course, we're going to use automation
and tools to help pull this part of the
system together so that the outreach
doesn't take you 10 hours a day to make
happen. But if you want to break through
this massive amount of AI slop that's in
my inbox is probably hitting your inbox
as well, then you need to send messages
that are actually good that actually
break through the noise that actually
deliver something of value to your
buyer. Your message must reference
something about their specific business,
their role, the problem they're facing
right now. You must show with a strong
hypothesis. And it doesn't matter if
your hypothesis is slightly off. You
want to be bold with your hypothesis
that you know what their issue is and
you know what their pain point is better
than what they do. And that's what
separates the messages that get ignored
or the ones that get thrown into your
spam folder versus the ones that start
conversations and book meetings in your
diary. And as a quick side note, I find
myself repeating regularly in our group
mentorship calls in in our mentorship
program that every single touch point
has one goal with your cold outreach and
that is get a meeting booked. This is
something that people tend to get wrong
when they first start working with us.
You are not here to pitch your service.
You're not here to explain the
deliverables. All we're trying to do is
just get them in a conversation with you
on the phone preferably or Zoom call,
Google Meets, whatever it may be. And
then we'll deal with all the other stuff
that we have to get through in our sales
process in the next step of the selling
system. So when lead generation runs as
a process instead of something that
you're you're doing randomly when you
just start crapping yourself at the end
of the month that there's no new client
meetings in the diary, you're going to
find yourself because you're putting
consistent effort in with consistent
results as well. The top of your
pipeline is going to stay full whether
you're in the the heaviest month of your
delivery of the year or not because the
sales system is going to be running in
the background regardless. But getting a
meeting booked in the diary is only half
of the job, right? Because well,
prospects are going to show up to that
call cold, skeptical, and with what I
call the sales shield up in between you
both. That they're going to be ready and
primed to say no. Or even worse, I'll
think about it, and then they never get
back to you. But we can turn that around
with what we do between the moment that
we book the meeting and the moment that
we engage with the prospect. And to make
this more real, I to think about what
the default experience looks like from a
prospect's side when they are dealing
with with service-based vendors. They
book a call. They probably know very
little about you because they booked a
call from an advert or a video or or
whatever it may be. And then the
prospect spends the first 10 minutes of
the conversation with the business
owner, with the salesperson deciding,
well, do I trust this individual to
solve my painful problem? And that is
from the business owner's perspective or
the salesperson's perspective. That's 10
minutes of of highstakes chess. And it
takes a lot of skill to build that trust
directly one-on-one when you're with
that person. Now, the better way to go
about doing this is to use the
indoctrination system. We teach this in
our mentorship, but this allows you to
build enough trust before the call. So,
you don't have to do any of that faffing
around on the call itself, and you can
get straight into the the delivery call
process without having to build a bunch
of trust before the person even opens
their ears to hearing what you've got to
say. And the idea behind all this is
pretty simple. before the prospect picks
up the phone to speak with you. Our goal
is that they know exactly what you do,
how you solve the problem, and why your
unique and interesting approach works.
And when the buyer understands all this
before the call itself, well, now
there's urgency for them to do something
on the call to make a decision rather
than just jumping on a call to to
investigate if this is a a potential
solution to their problem. And for
sales.com, I do this with a series of
emails that are written in a specific
way, whilst pushing people who book a
call to two more YouTube videos like
this. So they can binge watch another
two hours of of this ugly mug before
they jump on a call with the team. So
they already know basically whether they
trust me or they trust the service and
what we offer and they learn more about
the team and the offer. They get all
that from these kind of YouTube videos.
So when they jump on a call, they've had
a series of steps that have
indoctrinated them and they've also
hopefully consumed 1 hour, 2 hours, 3
hours of this content as well. So let me
give you a literal example from our
email sequence when people book a call.
So I send this exact email to people who
book a call with our team and it goes
something like, "Hey, looking forward to
speaking to you on our scheduled call.
Can you please take a look through the
short videos on this page? The videos
explain how the mentorship works, how
we're going to deliver you a positive
ROI within the first 30 days, and then
they answer some questions that you may
have right now. Watching the videos
means that we can have more time in our
call to dig into your situation and to
see if the salesman.com mentorship is
the right fit for your business. So,
they then click the link in the email.
It takes them through to this page where
I then deliver on the promises within
the email and I give them an additional
FAQ at the end of this page as well. And
this is really important because this
deals with most of the common sales
objections that we used to get on our
sales calls. And now once people see
this, they've been indoctrinated by the
answers to these FAQ questions. Now
these objections very rarely come up
anymore because again, we've dealt with
them ahead of time. And look, if you're
sat there watching this right now and
you're thinking, there's quite a lot of
stuff I've got to build here, Will, I
need a hand to build it. And you'd like
me and my team to help build this sales
system out for you, then click the link
in the video description below to book a
call with my team. We'll take a look at
your numbers. We'll see where you're
stuck. And if we can help, we'll offer
you a place in a mentorship, and then
you can potentially get started with us.
So, that's one example from the
indoctrination process. And what we're
trying to do here is engineer easier,
better, more productive sales calls
before they even jump on the call with
us. Okay? So, now the prospect is on the
call. And this is where most service
business owners undo everything that
their sales system has worked hard to
build up until this point. Because most
business owners, the moment someone
tells you their problem, they tend to
get excited. You you know that you can
help them. So you start explaining your
service, what makes you different, your
process, how it all works. And that push
to try and help your prospects in that
moment is what's causing them to go,
"Okay, I need to think about it." And
then they ghost you and never speak to
you again straight after the call wraps
up. So let's take a look at the steps
you need to go through on your discovery
calls to help the buyer say yes. So, in
a nutshell, what we're doing here is
questions first, solutions later, right?
So, drill this into your brain.
Questions first, solutions later. And I
always tell my clients to try and act
the best you can like a doctor. So, if
you went to a GP because you had a sore
leg, they wouldn't just take your word
for it that your leg was sore and then
prescribe you some pain relief and then
send you out the door, right? A doctor
would ask you some questions about,
well, when did the pain start? How
painful is it actually in the grand
scheme of things or on a scale of 1 to
10? What happens if you move your leg
one way or another? They might send you
for for an X-ray. They might send you
for a scan if they think that'll help.
And only then, only once they've
gathered all this information and
they've braced you as to how severe the
issue actually is, do they give the
diagnosis. And you need to do the same
on your discovery calls if you want to
convert more of your clients. Now, to
put this into practice, we need to go
through six main steps on our discovery
calls. First, pain. You got to ask what
happens if this doesn't get resolved.
You got to ask them who else this
affects. You want to go deep into
whether it affects them personally. If
they're the business owner you're
engaging with, like with my clients,
does it affect their family? Does it
affect their household? You want to go
deeper and deeper and deeper into the
pain. You basically want them to feel
the weight of the problem as as as
they're sat in front of you. You want
them to feel uncomfortable. You want
them to believe that they can't deal
with this on their own anymore. And then
second, we want to find the trigger that
led them to want to jump in this call in
the first place. So it's a it's a lost
client or a target that didn't get hit
or a competitor that appeared out of
nowhere that's coming along and might
take a whole chunk of their business.
Whatever it is, this is the specific
thing in this specific moment that's
going to drive the urgency across the
rest of the sales process. Third, we
want to help the prospect understand the
bigger, brighter, bolder future reality
that they'd be moving to if they solve
the problem and if they start working
with you. And this is important because
there's some people like myself, right?
I'm not really driven by running away
from pain. I will quite happily sit
through pain if it means that I get to
solve the problem myself. I'm more
motivated and you can easily pitch me
and and sell me on products and services
if you pitch me on moving towards a
brighter upside rather than away from
pain. So, we need to cover both bases
here. And the more that you can push the
current painful reality away from the
bigger, brighter, bolder future, you
pull them apart and then you position
your service as the bridge between the
two. The more excited this prospect is
going to be to get started with you, the
more urgency they're going to have to
say yes, hand over the cash, and just
get cracking. And then after this point
of emotional back and forth, ups and
downs on the call, we need to get back
to the nitty-gritty. The fourth thing
that we need to cover is the ROI. We
need to put rough numbers. Even if they
are very rough, we need to put them on
the table early. It doesn't need to be
precise. We don't need to have the exact
numbers jotted down right in front of
us. We just need rough numbers, but we
got to put something in front of the
prospect so they can see their problem
is going to be less painful. Even if
they got to spend some cash to resolve
it, we got to deliver essentially an
ROI. And this now is the turning point
in the call. This is where most business
owners start to get a little bit
uncomfortable. But you've got to ask
what can sometimes feel like it's not a
difficult question, but it sometimes
feels like a difficult question to ask.
You must clarify that the prospect has
the budget to work with you. Well, the
good news here is that if you ask about
the budget at this point in the call,
they're already going to be pretty sold
on working with you. And so, they're
going to happily share their finances.
And this step just goes straight by
pretty quickly. And it's never as
stressful as what most business owners
think it's going to be before they start
doing this routinely. And then for step
six, before you wrap up, you've got to
lock in the next step of the buyer's
journey. You need a specific time and a
date in both your calendar and their
calendar for whatever that next step may
be. Maybe it's a proposal. Maybe they
need to get other members of the team on
a call. Whatever it is, doesn't really
matter. It's got to be locked in both
your diaries. Otherwise, the discovery
call has not been completed. So,
indoctrinate your prospects. Work
through them with this discovery call
process. And you're gonna find them
literally asking towards the end of the
call, okay, how do I get started? And
that is obviously a massive buying
signal, and that tells you that the
process up until this point has worked.
Now, there is one final step that most
service business owners completely skip
when they are building out their sales
system, and it's the one thing that
kills deals that could have been
absolutely easy wins. Because even when
a prospect wants to work with you and
they've got the budget to get started,
there's often a logical rather than an
emotional hurdle for them to say yes and
paying the invoice. So that's what we're
going to tackle next. Okay. So think
about what happens the moment a prospect
has to justify their decision to work
with you to someone else within their
business. It could be a a business
partner. It could even be their boss, a
board member, even their spouse if it's
a if it's a small business, right? The
prospect is never going to be able to do
the same job as you are capable or your
sales team is capable of selling the
pain, positioning the bigger, brighter,
bolder future reality and all the
emotions that come with that. And to be
quite honest, in fact, most of the other
secondary decision makers who are
involved in the buying process, even if
they're just subtly involved in the
buying process, they don't care about
any of that stuff anyway. They just
typically want to understand the cold,
hard numbers behind the investment to
work for you. And this is where the
business case comes in. And even the
really successful clients in my
mentorship, they often miss this step in
their sales process before they start
working with me. And the results of
implementing it have been absolutely
crazy when it gets added in after the
fact. And this is because what it does
is it removes this last logical buy
between I want to do this and I'm doing
this. You're giving the buyer, you're
giving the prospect the maths to back up
their decision. So they don't have to
rely on the gut feelings that they had
on the call with you to then pitch those
feelings to other people that are around
them. You're giving them everything that
they need to fight their corner and
pitch the people that have a say on this
decision or that they feel like should
have a say on this decision before they
move forward with your offer. And to be
real with you here, I teach a slightly
more complex but persuasive structure in
my mentorship. But if you're not already
doing business cases, if you're not
already delivering them to your clients
after every single discovery call, then
this will do you fine. Let's start with
the basics. So, we need to explain in
the prospect's words from your discovery
call the situation they find themselves
in. Even better, right? If you've
recorded your discovery calls, you can
get them transcribed and then you can
quote the actual buyer in the document.
We all this cognitive bias. So, once we
say something, we want to remain
consistent with it. So, if you can use
the prospect's quotes in the document,
it makes all this a lot more persuasive.
Then, in the next step of the business
case, we want to document the financial
upside and the ROI of solving your
problem. And only once the ROI has been
established do you now start talking
about you and your deliverables and how
you intend to solve the problem. You've
got to make the solution seem fast,
easy, and cost effective as you wrap it
up and package it in this document. So
fast, easy, cost effective. And if you
do that, that's kind of it. Adding this
step alone can add 10 to 20% to the
conversion rate at this step of your
sales process. And once you put these
business cases together a couple of
times, a handful of times, two or three
times, you can use AI to automate all of
this as well. And when a clear ROI is on
the table and the prospect has the cold,
hard maths to convince themselves and
and anyone else within the account that
needs convincing that you are the
solution to the problem, it makes it
dead easy for them to say yes. So ICP,
meeting booking process, discovery call
process, a business case at the end of
it. That is a super basic sales system
that's guaranteed to add new revenue to
your business once it's implemented.
Now, when you get the sales system set
up and running, sales becomes simple and
predictable, just like the client
deliverable system that you've already
got in your business right now. And if
you want to hand get any of this set up,
book a call in our calendar and let's
see if we're a good fit to work
together. But there is another reason
other than just selling systems why most
service-based businesses don't break the
$1 million a year revenue number. And
it's got nothing to do with sales
systems, process, and all about your own
sales psychology. So, click up here to
watch this video where I explain how
you're getting in your own way when you
try and increase your revenue and
profits and what you should do about